S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literary and Art Magazine UP135
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literary and Art Magazine
2000 -- 2019
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office for Campus Life
UP135
0.25 Linear Feet
1 Web sites
5 Digital Object(s)
103 Megabytes
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series: S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literary and Art Magazine, S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literature and Arts Magazine, S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literary Arts and Music Magazine, and Web crawls.
Biographical / Historical
S.A.L.A.A.M. (South Asia Literary and Art Magazine) was a publication that was a sub-group of the Tufts Association of South Asians publication (TASA). It was founded by editors-in-chief Swati Mehta and Sarada Peri, and published its first issue in the Spring of 2000. It sought to publishd artwork, poetry, and prose by South Asian college students, both at Tufts and at schools in the greater Boston area.
The magazine appears to have halted production after the Spring 2007 issue, and to have been restarted in 2011 by Neha Madhusoodanan, changing its name in the process to South Asia Literature, Arts, and Music. Their presence was largely in print, distributing issues of the magazine on campus. However, they also maintained an online blog between July 2013 and December 2014, and a Facebook page between July 2013 and August 2015, sharing pieces in the magazine as well as news articles and videos relevant to the South Asian community. The Winter 2014-2015 print issue appears to have been the final issue of the magazine.
Scope and Contents
This collections contains issues of S.A.L.A.A.M. (South Asian Literary And Art Magazine/South Asia Literature, Arts, and Music). It was created by a sub-group of TASA (Tufts Association of South Asians) with the purpose of promoting the growth of creative writing and the visual arts among those of South Asian descent. It offered an outlet for experimentation and learning while recognizing and showcasing the talents of a people with connections to a subcontinent immensely rich in culture.
The collection also contains web crawls documenting the group's web presence.
- S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literary and Art Magazine, 2000 -- 2001; UP135.001; 0.1 Linear Feet; 2 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains S.A.L.A.A.M. (South Asian Literary And Art Magazine), a sub-group of TASA (Tufts Association of South Asians). It was created with the purpose of promoting the growth of creative writing and the visual arts among those of South Asian descent.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - S.A.L.A.A.M.: South Asian Literary and Arts Magazine, Spring, 2000; UP135.001.001.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 15 Megabytes (Box 1)
    Volume, issue
    1, 1
  - S.A.L.A.A.M.: South Asian Literary and Arts Magazine, Spring, 2001; UP135.001.001.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 1)
    2, 1
- S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literature and Arts Magazine, 2004 -- 2007; UP135.000011; 0.1 Linear Feet; 3 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains S.A.L.A.A.M. (South Asian Literature and Arts Magazine), a sub-group of TASA (Tufts Association of South Asians). It was created with the purpose of promoting the growth of creative writing and the visual arts among those of South Asian descent.
  - S.A.L.A.A.M.: South Asian Literary and Arts Magazine, Spring, 2004; UP135.001.001.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 26 Megabytes (Box 1)
    5, 1
  - S.A.L.A.A.M.: South Asian Literary and Arts Magazine, Spring, 2005; UP135.001.001.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 21 Megabytes (Box 1)
    6, 1
  - S.A.L.A.A.M.: South Asian Literary and Arts Magazine, Spring, 2007; UP135.001.001.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 20 Megabytes (Box 1)
    8, 1
- S.A.L.A.A.M, South Asian Literary Arts and Music Magazine, circa 2015; UP135.000012; 0.1 Linear Feet
  This series contains S.A.L.A.A.M. (South Asian Literary Arts and Music Magazine), a sub-group of TASA (Tufts Association of South Asians). It was created with the purpose of promoting the growth of creative writing and the visual arts among those of South Asian descent.
  - S.A.L.A.A.M.: South Asian Literary and Arts Magazine, circa 2015; UP135.000010 (Box 1)
- Web crawls, 2015 -- 2019; UP135.002; 1 Web sites
  Quarterly web crawls of the Salaam website crawled by DCA, as part of the Student Organizations web collection, to document the presesence of Tufts University student organizations on the web.
  Other Finding Aids
  To see all of websites crawled as part of the Student Organizations web collection, please visit https://archive-it.org/collections/6387
  - Salaam, 2015 -- 2019; UP135.002.00001
    General
    Frequency: quarterly crawl. (Inactive)